<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics Group @ ISU</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Graphics Group @ ISU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Extraction for Handwritten Text</title>
      <link>/2018/02/information-extraction-for-handwritten-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/information-extraction-for-handwritten-text/</guid>
      <description>In forensic handwriting applications practitioners are interested in matching a document with an unknown author with a particular person’s writing style. In order for this to be done computationally it is necessary to first process the documents and try to isolate information in the messy documents. Starting with just blobs of ink, we will isolate important characteristics and start to make steps towards having something usable for performing analyses. This talk will introduce a Shiny app that shows off some of the handwriting processing, and will delve into the Rcpp code that makes it go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blogdown quick tutorial</title>
      <link>/2018/02/blogdown-quick-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/blogdown-quick-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I will show you how to create a professional academic homepage (or blog) from scratch using the R package ‘blogdown’. I will first introduce some basic concepts of web construction and some essential tools (‘rmarkdown’ and ‘git/github’) that will be used in building websites with ‘blogdown’. Then I will illustrate how to build a website step by step. By the end of the meeting, you are expected to have your own homepage created!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recreating Historical Graphics with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/2018/01/recreating-historical-graphics-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/recreating-historical-graphics-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>At the turn of the 19th century, there seemed to have been a sudden interest in the United States in visualizing census data. There are some pretty amazing plots from this time in “The Statistical Atlas of the United States” and in the collection “African American Photographs Assembled for 1900 Paris Exposition” by W.E.B. Du Bois. In this talk, I’ll walk through the process of recreating a small sample of these visualizations using the NHGIS data finder and modern statistical computing tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>